

Joshua Cyrenian





Vancouver, BC 1-604-442-4464 joshua@cyrenian.me

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

SKILLS

An experienced software developer and leader of 10+ years with 10 years of frontend development, and 6 years of full-stack web and mobile development. I'm dedicated, determined, and adaptable. Looking to work for a company with a positive and collaborative, team environment.

- React
- Redux
- **TypeScript**
- **JavaScript**
- HTML/CSS
- Java (Web Development)

- .NET Development (C#, VB.NET, T-SQL)
- iOS Development (Objective-C, Swift)
- Android Development (Java, Kotlin)
- Agile/ Scrum
- **Process Documentation**
- **Technical Project Management**

WORK HISTORY

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

04/2023 to Present

Insurance Corporation of British Columbia (ICBC) | Vancouver, BC

Accomplishments:

Delivered high-quality products by partnering with team members and across the department and business stakeholders to develop new features and fix defects within the insurance broker application called PolicyCenter as well as the online renewal portal for ICBC customers. I modified PolicyCenter on the backend using Java, Gosu, and XML on the frontend; and JavaScript and React for the online renewal portal's frontend. These changes impacted 3.6 million people and over 900 autoplan brokers across the province.

Responsibilities:

- Providing technical expertise while managing and leading medium to high complex work for the design, configuration, development, and delivery of software applications.
- Investigation and resolution of production problems related to the applications. Providing estimates for business cases, impact assessments, projects and action requests in response to requests from Business Systems Analysts or Team Leads.
- Develop automation methods, identify performance and system capacity requirements, and implement development tools to gain efficiencies with application development and operational support.
- Review and check the work of junior developers.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

06/2022 to 01/2023

Crossplay Digital | Vancouver, BC

Accomplishments:

In this contract position, I collaborated with designers by converting Figma designs into reusable, modular React components using StoryBook. This allowed me to meet tight deadlines and isolate and test each component.

The main goal of this project was to create an engaging UI for crossword puzzle solvers to play games and interact with other users, as well as an administration/analytics UI for puzzle constructors. This time-sensitive and intensive project was successfully completed with the release of the first MVP.

Responsibilities:

- Provided consulting services on UI best practices, as well as analysis of user behaviour and feedback
- Implemented designs from Figma and other design platforms to web
- Used technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, and React (with various libraries like MUI, React Router, Webpack) to replicate designs and add functionality

Attended and participated in daily Scrum meetings

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER/IMPLEMENTATION CONSULTANT

06/2018 to 06/2022

commercebuild | Vancouver, BC

Achievements:

I worked on and completed many eCommerce websites (100+) by creating responsive, reusable templates. My duties also involved writing custom functionality, using JavaScript and React, for customers. These websites were performant and were built for enterprise level companies as Mitsubishi. These companies all saw at least a 15% increase in sales after go-live.

Responsibilities:

- Team lead for website design and implementation of user experiences.
- Mentored junior and intermediate designers with guidance of eCommerce UI best practices, latest front-end programming technologies and methodologies, and training/troubleshooting sessions.
- Assisted commercebuild clients with creating their web stores according to design specifications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Implemented custom UI/UX solutions for commercebuild clients through Jira ticketing platform, utilizing Scrum and Agile practices
- Provided consulting, training services, and eCommerce solutions to clients based on business and technical requirements

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

06/2015 to 07/2017

05/2015

Pan Pacific Pet | Abbotsford, BC

Achievements:

Re-architected eCommerce platforms, as well as the iOS catalog app. This included building an API that retrieved data from the database and served data to both mediums. Due to the new, polished user interfaces, increased performance, and new customer service features, product sales raised by roughly \$2-3 million within just the first year.

Also built multitude of internal applications that empowered employees by increasing efficiency and productivity. Some examples include an expense application for employees, a CRM, and a CMS that allowed employees to manage content served on the web.

Responsibilities:

- Analyzed and reported on statistics and processes for use and development of various software applications
- Team lead on design, UI, and UX of new website and iOS application (main eCommerce platforms for sales)
- Participated in daily Scrum meetings, maintained sprint backlogs, and utilized Scrum framework and Agile best practices when implementing projects.
- Wrote internal and customer-facing applications using C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, VB.NET, Objective-C, and Swift
- Supported customers and employees on use of all customer applications

EDUCATION

Diploma | Computer Systems Technology

British Columbia Institute of Technology, Burnaby, BC

Diploma | IOS Development

Lighthouse Labs, Vancouver, BC

Certificate | Marketing Management 06/2012

British Columbia Institute of Technology, Vancouver, BC

CERTIFICATIONS O Professional Scrum Master I (PSM I) - Scrum.org